<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news</id>
    <title>UNC Chapel Hill AAUP</title>
    <updated>2026-02-12T18:16:52.710Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <author>
        <name>UNC-CH AAUP</name>
        <email>info@unc-ch-aaup.org</email>
        <uri>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/feed.atom"/>
    <subtitle>UNC Chapel Hill chapter of the American Association of University Professors</subtitle>
    <logo>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/favicon-32x32.png</logo>
    <icon>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UNC-CH AAUP statement on classroom recording policy]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-02-12</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-02-12"/>
        <updated>2026-02-12T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The UNC-Chapel Hill Chapter of AAUP opposes classroom recording for
any reason without the instructor’s consent. We were shocked to learn
on Monday February 9th that the Interim Provost had drafted a new
policy allowing the recording of classes to go into effect on Monday
February 16th.</p>
<p>Read the rest of the <a href="/assets/statement-on-classroom-recording-policy.pdf">UNC-CH AAUP statement on classroom recording
policy</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[February 2, 2026 Weekly Update]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-02-02</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-02-02"/>
        <updated>2026-02-02T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Academic Freedom Code for UNC System</h3>
<p>Last week the UNC System Board of Governors &quot;<a href="https://www.wunc.org/education/2026-01-28/nc-professors-fear-new-academic-freedom-policy-censor-faculty">unanimously approved the
System&#39;s academic freedom
definition</a>,&quot;
which seeks to set
&quot;<a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/faculty-issues/academic-freedom/2026/01/29/unc-plans-define-what-academic-freedom-and-isnt">limits</a>&quot;
on academic freedom, and put it forward for a binding vote at their
next meeting on Feb. 25th. The NC AAUP&#39;s Syllabus Committee (including
members from our chapter) will communicate a statewide strategy in
advance of the BoG mtg.</p>
<p>You can read <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1y5uv1atZ6xoUiToNH_UcvswTWsXmB1prhZDZo1fif80/edit?tab=t.0">the proposed revised
policy</a>. Be
sure to note the &quot;system suggestions in red.&quot;</p>
<p>See the <a href="/assets/letter-re-proposed-changes-to-academic-freedom-code-2026-01-26.pdf">letter from AAUP&#39;s
lawyers</a>
to the UNC System about the proposed policy revisions. <strong>Please
circulate this letter widely.</strong></p>
<h3>Syllabus Requests</h3>
<p><strong>If you receive a public records request for a syllabus, please share
it -- and any subsequent correspondence -- with the NC AAUP hotline at
<a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/projects/providing-legal-support">https://www.aaupnc.org/projects/providing-legal-support</a>.</strong></p>
<p>The hotline can confidentially provide support and first-line legal
advice. Compiling as much info as possible will also help us build a
legal case against the UNC system and the syllabus policy.</p>
<p><strong>Please also continue to share with colleagues the NC AAUP&#39;s
&quot;<a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/projects/guidance-for-syllabi">Guidelines for
Syllabi</a>,&quot; and
encourage them to share with the hotline any requests they receive.</strong></p>
<h3>Duke AAUP Cut the Cuts Rally</h3>
<h4>Friday Feb. 6th, 4:30pm, Duke East Campus</h4>
<p>UNC CH AAUP, UE150, and TransparUNCy are collaborating with Duke and
several other organizations for a Durham-based Cut the Cuts
rally. This is an opportunity for cross institutional solidarity in
the face of ideological cuts to staff and services at public and
private universities. (Following our lead, our AAUP colleagues at Duke
commissioned their own independent audit). Please consider joining
this Friday, February 6th at Trinity Park in Durham, 4:30 pm. <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/12ExcLLP89V1BA8P2yHY63dD1Ndoi4m5d/view">More
info.</a></p>
<h3>Area Studies Centers closings</h3>
<p>The Faculty Executive Council passed <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/12ExcLLP89V1BA8P2yHY63dD1Ndoi4m5d/view">this
resolution</a>
in support of the centers.</p>
<h3>Chapter Organizing</h3>
<p>Our chapter has formed a <strong>faculty governance working group</strong>. The
committee will continue to report at our Friday meetings.</p>
<p>We are looking for a few <strong>volunteers to run our chapter elections</strong>,
slated for April. Election committee members are responsible for
soliciting nominations for officer terms beginning in June and running
the election. <strong>If you do not plan to run for office and would like to
be involved, please email Rosie Miesner:
<a href="mailto:rose.miesner@gmail.com">rose.miesner@gmail.com</a></strong></p>
<p>Several of our chapter members are participating in the <strong>National
AAUP &quot;Organize Every Campus&quot; training in February 2026.</strong> If you are
looking for ways to join other colleagues to more effectively resist
the far right&#39;s and UNC&#39;s violations of academic freedom, threats of
violence and harassment, this training could be for you!</p>
<p>&quot;Organize Every Campus&quot; training will take place over 5 sessions on
<strong>Mondays and Wednesdays, February 2, 4, 9, 11 and 18, from 6:30
PM-8:30 PM ET</strong>. Participants are expected to attend the entire
training for all five sessions, since each session builds on the
previous ones. In order to sign up, you do not have to register
directly. <strong>Email Don Nonini at
<a href="mailto:dnonini@gmail.com">dnonini@gmail.com</a> you are interested in
participating in these sessions, or have questions.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Our next weekly working meeting will be Friday, January 30th, from Noon-1pm.</strong></p>
<p>All UNC instructors are welcome to attend, to help strategize about
the area studies closures, the syllabus policy, academic freedom, and
to bring other issues for us to discuss as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1">https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1</a></p>
<p><strong>If you are interested in serving as a liaison for your department or
unit, please email Erik Gellman at
<a href="mailto:esgellman@gmail.com">esgellman@gmail.com</a>.</strong></p>
<p>If you would like to help with these updates or with our chapter&#39;s
website and social media, email Michael Palm at
<a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/">NC AAUP</a></strong> is the fastest-growing
non-union AAUP chapter in the country.</p>
<p>Encourage colleagues to <a href="https://www.aaup.org/join">join</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[January 26, 2026 Weekly Update]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-01-26</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-01-26"/>
        <updated>2026-01-26T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Syllabus Requests, Committee, and Q&amp;A Sessions</h3>
<p>If you receive a public records request for a syllabus, please share
it with the NC AAUP hotline at
<a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/projects/providing-legal-support">https://www.aaupnc.org/projects/providing-legal-support</a> The hotline
can confidentially provide support and first-line legal advice.
Compiling as much info as possible will also help us build a legal
case against the UNC system and the syllabus policy.</p>
<p>The NC AAUP Syllabus Committee has scheduled three Zoom meetings at
different times, hopefully accommodating different schedules, to field
questions live:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Monday, January 26 from 5-6 PM</strong> (one of our attorneys will be
present at this one)</li>
<li><strong>Friday, January 30 from 9-10 AM</strong></li>
<li><strong>Monday, February 2 from 1-2 PM</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Please register for the first meeting here:</p>
<p><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/meeting/register/Q_RqCIeBTuCcQiD5lozTlg#/registration">https://us06web.zoom.us/meeting/register/Q_RqCIeBTuCcQiD5lozTlg#/registration</a></p>
<p>If you are interested in joining the NC AAUP Syllabus Committee,
contact Michael Palm <a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Academic Freedom Code for UNC System and Working Group</h3>
<p>The UNC System Board of Governors is <a href="https://www.theassemblync.com/news/education/higher-education/unc-system-board-governors-parameters-academic-freedom/">poised to define—and
restrict—academic freedom</a>. You can read <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1y5uv1atZ6xoUiToNH_UcvswTWsXmB1prhZDZo1fif80/edit?tab=t.0">the proposed revised
policy</a>. Be sure to note the “system suggestions in red.”</p>
<p>If you would like to join a group working to protect academic freedom
at UNC-Chapel Hill, contact Michael Palm at
<a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Faculty Governance Interest Survey and Working Group</h3>
<p>If you would like to join a working group of chapter members
interested in working with faculty governance groups, contact Mehdi
Shadmehr: <a href="mailto:mshadmeh@gmail.com">mshadmeh@gmail.com</a></p>
<p>Faculty governance interest survey closes tomorrow (Tuesday) at
midnight. Though the administration is undermining faculty governance
at every opportunity, these positions provide a public venue for
expressing collective concerns and registering resistance. Please
consider registering your interest in participating. No blood
sacrifice required, you will have a chance to change your mind before
April elections. Search your UNC inbox for &quot;Reminder to take the
Faculty Governance Interest Survey.&quot;</p>
<h3>Election Committee Volunteers</h3>
<p>We are looking for a few volunteers to run our chapter elections,
slated for April. Election committee members are responsible for
soliciting nominations for officer terms beginning in June and running
the election. If you do not plan to run for office and would like to
be involved, please email Rosie Miesner:
<a href="mailto:rose.miesner@gmail.com">rose.miesner@gmail.com</a></p>
<h3>Chapter Organizing</h3>
<p><strong>Our next weekly working meeting will be Friday, January 30th, from Noon-1pm.</strong></p>
<p>All UNC instructors are welcome to attend, to help strategize about
the area studies closures, the syllabus policy, academic freedom, and
to bring other issues for us to discuss as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1">https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1</a></p>
<p>If you are interested in serving as a liaison for your department or
unit, please email Erik Gellman at
<a href="mailto:esgellman@gmail.com">esgellman@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>If you would like to help with these updates or with our chapter&#39;s
website and social media, email Michael Palm at
<a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/">NC AAUP</a> is the fastest-growing non-union
AAUP chapter in the country. Encourage colleagues to join at
<a href="https://www.aaup.org/join">https://www.aaup.org/join</a>.</p>
<p><strong>National AAUP</strong> is offering its next <strong>&quot;Organize Every Campus&quot; or
&quot;Skills to Win&quot; training in February 2026.</strong> If you are looking for
ways to join other colleagues to more effectively resist the far
right&#39;s and UNC&#39;s violations of academic freedom, threats of violence
and harassment, this training could be right for you! &quot;Organize Every
Campus&quot; training will take place over 5 sessions on <strong>Mondays and
Wednesdays, February 2, 4, 9, 11 and 18, from 6:30 PM-8:30 PM
ET</strong>. Participants are expected to attend the entire training for all
five sessions, since each session builds on the previous ones. In
order to sign up, you do not have to register directly. Email Don
Nonini at <a href="mailto:dnonini@gmail.com">dnonini@gmail.com</a> if you are
interested in participating in these sessions, or have questions.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[January 19, 2026 Weekly Update]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-01-19</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2026-01-19"/>
        <updated>2026-01-19T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>TODAY: Protecting Noncitizens, 5-6pm</h3>
<p>AAUP NC has organized an info session for Monday, January 19, 5-6 pm,
about ways to protect the rights of noncitizen faculty, students, and
staff on our campuses. We&#39;ll hear from AAUP senior counsel Aaron
Nisenson; and learn from faculty members about models and plans for
protecting noncitizens on campus, as well as where and how to work
with local groups, such as Siembra NC, in the broader community. We&#39;ll
also talk about how to pressure/encourage university administrations
to better communicate with and protect their noncitizen communities.</p>
<p>To register:
<a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/meeting/register/GjG7tINsTxuZlSgGl4DlaQ#/registration">https://us06web.zoom.us/meeting/register/GjG7tINsTxuZlSgGl4DlaQ#/registration</a></p>
<p>All are welcome. Please share.</p>
<h3>TOMORROW: TransparUNCy teach-in about Area Studies Centers closures</h3>
<p><strong>TransparUNCy</strong> is hosting a <strong>teach-in</strong> <strong>tomorrow, Jan. 20, 4:30pm</strong>
in 3411 Student Union. You can follow TransparUNCy at
<a href="https://substack.com/@transparuncy">https://substack.com/@transparuncy</a> and
<a href="https://www.instagram.com/transparuncy/">https://www.instagram.com/transparuncy/</a>.</p>
<p>Personal letters to administrators with details about the importance
of the centers and the impact of their closure on UNC&#39;s reputation
are also reportedly having an impact.</p>
<p>Roberts, Lee Harriss<br><a href="mailto:lhrunc@email.unc.edu">lhrunc@email.unc.edu</a></p>
<p>Knuffman, Nathan L<br><a href="mailto:nknuffman@unc.edu">nknuffman@unc.edu</a></p>
<p>White, James William Carl<br><a href="mailto:jwcwhite@email.unc.edu">jwcwhite@email.unc.edu</a></p>
<p>Dean, Jr., James W.<br><a href="mailto:James.Dean@unc.edu">James.Dean@unc.edu</a></p>
<p>And keep circulating the results of the independent audit of UNC we
co-sponsored last Fall.</p>
<h3>Faculty Governance working group</h3>
<p>If you would like to join a working group of chapter members
interested in working with faculty governance groups, contact Mehdi
Shadmehr: <a href="mailto:mshadmeh@gmail.com">mshadmeh@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><strong>Our next weekly working meeting will be Friday, January 16th, from
Noon-1pm.</strong> All UNC instructors are welcome to attend, to help
strategize about the area studies closures, the syllabus policy, and
to bring other issues for us to discuss as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1">https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1</a></p>
<p>If you are interested in serving as a liaison for your department or
unit, please email Erik Gellman at
<a href="mailto:esgellman@gmail.com">esgellman@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>If you would like to help with these updates or with our chapter&#39;s
website and social media, email Michael Palm at
<a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/">NC AAUP</a> is the fastest-growing non-union
AAUP chapter in the country. Encourage colleagues to join at
<a href="https://www.aaup.org/join">https://www.aaup.org/join</a>.</p>
<p><strong>National AAUP</strong> is offering its next <strong>&quot;Organize Every Campus&quot; or
&quot;Skills to Win&quot; training in February 2026.</strong> If you are looking for
ways to join other colleagues to more effectively resist the far
right&#39;s and UNC&#39;s violations of academic freedom, threats of violence
and harassment, this training could be right for you!  &quot;Organize Every
Campus&quot; training will take place over 5 sessions on <strong>Mondays and
Wednesdays, February 2, 4, 9, 11 and 18, from 6:30 PM-8:30 PM
ET</strong>. Participants are expected to attend the entire training for all
five sessions, since each session builds on the previous ones. In
order to sign up, you do not have to register directly.  Email Don
Nonini at <a href="mailto:dnonini@gmail.com">dnonini@gmail.com</a> if you are
interested in participating in these sessions, or have questions.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joint Statement on U.S. Customs and Border Protection Presence at UNC-Chapel Hill]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-11-19</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-11-19"/>
        <updated>2025-11-19T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today the UNC-Chapel Hill chapter of the AAUP, UE 150, and TransparUNCy sent <a href="/assets/joint-statement-on-uscbp-at-unc-ch.pdf">a joint statement</a> to Chancellor Roberts, Interim Provost Dean, Dean White, and Dean Rieckenberg demanding that UNC Chapel Hill ensure the safety of its students and staff in the face of domestic terrorism.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is in UNC Chapel Hill’s Wallet?]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-11-18</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-11-18"/>
        <updated>2025-11-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In his November 13 presentation, independent auditor Dr. Howard Bunsis
(Professor of Accounting, Eastern Michigan University) posed the
question to everyone in the audience, “Why is a university with a AAA
bond rating and billions in reserves considering layoffs and cutting
budgets?”  UNC Chapel Hill learned this week that all three
independent bond rating agencies -- Moodys, S&amp;P, and Fitch -- gave it
an outstanding AAA bond rating, placing it in a small minority of
universities at the top rank. Not only that, the University currently
has $1.9 billion in unrestricted reserves, and $1 billion cash on
hand. Bunsis made it clear that one of the things the University is
dedicated to is spending its money on high-level administrators and
their salaries. From 2016-2024, the number of administrators in Chapel
Hill has increased by 51.1%, but the full-time faculty by only 10.8%,
and the staff has been shrunk by 5.3%. Over the same period,
administrators’ salaries in the UNC budget have increased by 106%, but
the instructional budget only by 36.2%, and research budget by
41.7%. Yet the Chapel Hill administration and its Board of Trustees
are seeking to implement a $70 million austerity cut.</p>
<p>Michael Palm, President of the AAUP chapter, UNC Chapel Hill, stated:
“This audit lays bare the truth: any cuts to programs or personnel at
UNC-Chapel Hill are the result of political pressure, not financial
constraints. UNC’s budgeting decisions must be transparent and
inclusive of students, faculty, and staff as well as accountants,
lawyers, and administrators.”</p>
<p><a href="/assets/external-audit-2025-11-13.pdf">Read the full press release</a>
and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ULAvWgrjDc">watch the
presentation</a> revealing
that the university is in stellar financial condition, has a huge
buildup in administrators and their salaries, but seeks to impose a
$70 million cut on its lowest-paid staff.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Update November 10 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-11-10</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-11-10"/>
        <updated>2025-11-10T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>UNC Audit Analysis Presentation</h3>
<h4>Thursday, 11/13 @ 5:30 pm, Kerr Hall 1001</h4>
<p>Please join us in person or virtually to receive the findings from
Howard Bunsis&#39;s independent audit of UNC finances. Bunsis&#39;s analysis
equips us with data to challenge ServiceFirst austerity measures to
reduce faculty and staff numbers, salaries, and benefits.</p>
<p>The presentation begins at 5:30 pm and will be followed by a Q&amp;A. The
main entrance to Kerr will be unlocked until 5:45, though facilitators
will be available to let you in if you&#39;re arriving late.</p>
<p>The event is especially exciting as it represents a collaborative
effort between UE 150 (grad students and staff workers), UNC-AAUP
(us), and TransparUNCy (undergraduates).</p>
<p>Registration here! <a href="https://tinyurl.com/2025-ue-aaup-audit">https://tinyurl.com/2025-ue-aaup-audit</a></p>
<h3>No Compact for Higher Ed at UNC</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.wral.com/news/education/unc-chapel-hill-rejects-trump-education-compact-november-2025/">After the rally Friday led by Sunrise UNC and other student groups,
Chancellor Roberts said at the Faculty Council meeting that afternoon
that UNC would not agree to the Trump administration&#39;s Compact for
Higher
Ed.</a>
See <a href="/assets/aaup-vs-compact.pdf">the statement we distributed at the
meeting</a>.</p>
<h3>No new accreditor for UNC (at least for now)</h3>
<p>At the Faculty Council meeting, Provost Dean said UNC-CH would go with
the same accreditor in 2027, rather than <a href="https://www.theassemblync.com/education/unc-cphe-college-accreditation/">switching to
CPHE</a>,
which met with applause. Last week the UNC-Charlotte AAUP chapter
published this powerful <a href="https://www.ninertimes.com/opinion/letter-to-the-editor-prevent-the-floridification-of-north-carolina-accreditation/article_0ea23377-0195-459d-8af3-7571d106cb68.html">letter to the
editor</a>
outlining the stakes of the CPHE.</p>
<h3>Discriminating Against Dissent</h3>
<p>Read the AAUP-MESA report on <a href="https://mesana.org/pdf/Discriminating_Against_Dissent_Report.pdf">The Weaponization of Civil Rights Law to
Repress Campus Speech on
Palestine</a>.</p>
<h3>The NC AAUP provides free legal help for members</h3>
<p>If you feel you need to speak to a lawyer about violations of your
rights or about the state of the law surrounding academic freedom and
free speech, contact <a href="https://www.aaupnc.org/">https://www.aaupnc.org/</a>.</p>
<h3>Chapter Organizing</h3>
<p>We&#39;re identifying chapter liaisons for departments and academic
units. If you&#39;d like to volunteer, contact Erik Gellman at
<a href="mailto:esgellman@gmail.com">esgellman@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>If you would like to help with these weekly updates or help maintain
and update our chapter&#39;s website and social media, please contact
Michael Palm at <a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>And everyone is welcome to join our weekly working meetings Fridays
from Noon-1pm, even if just to say hi and see what&#39;s going on.</p>
<p><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1">https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Update October 27 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-10-27</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-10-27"/>
        <updated>2025-10-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>BSM Town Hall</h3>
<h4>Monday 10/27 6pm, Hitchcock Multipurpose Room, Stone Center</h4>
<p>The Black Student Movement will be hosting a Town Hall on Monday,
October 27th, at 6:00 PM in the Hitchcock Room of the Stone
Center. The objective of this event is to strengthen and unify the
Black community at Carolina. During the Town Hall, we will discuss
matters related to Upendo Lounge, clarify any confusion, and answer
any questions students, staff, and alumni may have. We are inviting
all Black organizations, faculty, and alumni to join us in this
important conversation. This space was not only taken from BSM as an
organization but from us collectively as a community. So, we&#39;re
looking for your support, presence, and engagement as we work together
to reclaim and restore it.</p>
<h3>Worker Health Care Plan Teach-In</h3>
<h4>Tuesday 10/28 6pm</h4>
<p>UE 150 is hosting a virtual teach-in on the current State Health Plan
and rising costs in NC. <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeqpuzsTvFB9QcOOKDLqIcGHdmwvfhgjHEtZy6MF1Bwq5wsnQ/viewform?link_id=3&can_id=73685a8fc37557b2f9414e42b1d80148&source=email-durham-endorsements-duke-founders-day-rally-more-2&email_referrer=email_2927359&email_subject=save-the-date-oct-28-aetna-exposed-teach-in-campaign-launch-worker-health-not-corporate-wealth">RSVP
here.</a></p>
<h3>AAUP Webinar in support of the upcoming 11/7 Day of Action</h3>
<h4>Tuesday 10/28 5-6pm</h4>
<p>AAUP members, check your email for a link to register.</p>
<h3>Day of Action for Higher Ed!</h3>
<h4>Friday 11/7 1:15pm, Polk Place</h4>
<p>Join Sunrise UNC and other campus groups! As students organize for
educational access and affordability, the freedom to learn, campus
safety, and a better future, the AFT and AUUP along with cross-sector
higher education unions are standing shoulder to shoulder in
solidarity.</p>
<h3>Academic Freedom at the next Faculty Council meeting</h3>
<h4>Friday 11/7 3-5pm, Kerr Hall</h4>
<p>Chapter members will present on academic freedom—what it means, its
history, and the urgent need to protect it today—at the next Faculty
Council Meeting, Friday, November 7, from 3-5pm, 1001 Kerr Hall. Join
us!</p>
<h3>Report on UNC Audit</h3>
<h4>Thursday 11/13 5:30-8pm, Carr Hall</h4>
<p>Howard Bunsis will share the findings from his independent audit of
UNC. Our chapter secured a grant from the NC AAUP to help fund this
audit. Howard will report for an hour, followed by 90 minutes
of Q&amp;A. Co-sponsored by UE150 and TransparUNCy.</p>
<h3>3 petitions to sign rejecting Trump Loyalty Oaths for Higher Ed</h3>
<ul>
<li>From <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdX_lzLLjYBW1UWQdTwJj-iCFEnNSwNZSnV1an2XPkHLGDGqA/viewform">UNC students</a></li>
<li>From the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScHFN2zZ2EYoyxAzJFLvDBed53P0hVBLxhMJICYDtQwNdWGSQ/viewform">Coalition for Carolina</a></li>
<li>From <a href="https://actionnetwork.org/petitions/university-administrations-reject-trumps-loyalty-oath-compacts/">a coalition of progressive groups including the national AAUP</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Our chapter voted to collectively endorse this one, but you can also
sign as an individual.</p>
<h3>DTH Faculty Free Speech Survey</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.dailytarheel.com/article/22332c16-e2e4-4e18-8fcb-88b9cb5de402">Fill out the DTH Faculty Free Speech Survey!</a></p>
<h3>Reclaim the Narrative: Higher Ed for the Common Good</h3>
<h3>Wednesday 10/29, 2-4pm</h3>
<p>The AAUP, Stand Together, and PEN America invite you to join <a href="https://click.actionnetwork.org/ss/c/u001.v2UrIOJHHKkg0Pk-aGvhy_TtrWBBAnh9vPhfXW55SOYJbs4UkOgVYzt8AGOsvCuM8gZJ0RVux7CrOgubSYvMNTk4A9IkZUOET957R2-K-tZbpVt8n-6NaUCVJSxnQVepEtSFzgKI-XKUphyKbiFmrwb7AGIS05vNUf1syOpOTsvGg8tNXq9hPE0T6RcIXbj95Uu4mVEmxfbjvPCrt0gV329B84gEZHHlJLRYj3Xvre0GatTmgQwy0ttXI4JF3j3RnJu8CNONA5oQUYY6EtgELYCJkEBruraEuZYSX8rE46Fi8zUr-ayklotycwaN7w4OrvDA4tjK23WedvRkR4SbPZB0W0YTMopfp26kKFs_GyYAc3ST4_vjvvEt9p5Tl2pP1Z9xp97tiZKaYmYAFeD4Wg/4kx/wlJARCmUR0qLtyyOuFWmgw/h1/h001.82YkajKlFdDdTm8lywZGEdLlOM3WD0GKb-4yv8_PHVs">Reclaim
the Narrative: Higher Ed for the Common
Good</a>,
a two-hour training webinar will equip you with practical tools to
tell your story and amplify the value of higher education in public
life.</p>
<p>Higher education is under coordinated attack, from funding cuts and
DEI bans to assaults on tenure, free speech, and the safety of
international scholars and students. Our individual stories of how our
work in higher education makes a difference are the most powerful
antidote to the misinformation campaign against higher
education. Truth is resistance.  Every story we can share with the
public pushes back against false narratives that paint higher ed as
elitist and broken.</p>
<p>In this training, you&#39;ll learn how to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Write powerful op-eds and letters to the editor</li>
<li>Use social media to reach wider audiences</li>
<li>Prepare for media interviews with confidence</li>
<li>Adapt these materials to host Reclaim the Narrative workshops on
your own campus</li>
</ul>
<p>AAUP members can <a href="https://click.actionnetwork.org/ss/c/u001.v2UrIOJHHKkg0Pk-aGvhy_TtrWBBAnh9vPhfXW55SOYJbs4UkOgVYzt8AGOsvCuM8gZJ0RVux7CrOgubSYvMNc6SfTRYzf9yRwT_fRjDogACze-wE9R7sFohvLW3fXA8kqRG5KM5znkvPSgjdzRKXUFzaxd8RRi0Vig27Ke3OiNxwVKhBRQmPbN-PKecWICGrgQxVgY70GqwoLh_EOgWJrPV-b_MvnXHzKIi5DHT1_oCGlKBoetZ6aYvMqUgT0FJSvSfFBZa7cyDc8g0XCv-HG-WuO6CjO_iKXXBrKaa6gDKFu71gY7OESw9GsDEMU3DhHorgM2bjeGPl2tvv0z24mxcJBQlsRtv6yJ9SRhD2ck0rB9Lt9bi5GMgJA6oGhtTnFpvzMLZusk-9QCC3D070g/4kx/wlJARCmUR0qLtyyOuFWmgw/h2/h001.pTWo6PN5UepanP5AqlkJrt-pct9T6OaIYU8uUcpXTyA">register
here</a>
to attend. Together, we can reclaim the story of higher education as a
public good essential to democracy.</p>
<h3>Chapter Organizing</h3>
<p>We&#39;re identifying chapter liaisons for departments and academic
units.  If you&#39;d like to volunteer, contact Erik Gellman at
<a href="mailto:esgellman@gmail.com">esgellman@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>If you would like to help with these weekly updates or help maintain
and update our chapter&#39;s website and social media, please contact
Michael Palm at <a href="http://gmail.com/">mwpalm@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>And everyone is welcome to join our <strong>weekly working meetings Fridays
from Noon-1pm</strong>, even if just to say hi and see what&#39;s going on:</p>
<p><a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1">https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89195114865?pwd=qf2kY5jKF6utphBBKn4ghkszHa6lLT.1</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Update October 6 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-10-06</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-10-06"/>
        <updated>2025-10-06T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Congrats to our colleague Dwayne Dixon on returning to the classroom!</h3>
<p>Read <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1eLrb98o3HLmJCvqymd7aW6bzGBPXyJHtNcxKBSsMyjk/edit?tab=t.0">Professor Dixon’s
statement</a>
and <a href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/assets/unc-ch-aaup-statement-on-dwayne-dixon.pdf">our statement calling for his
reinstatement</a>.</p>
<h3>AAUP Press Conference @ UNC: Wednesday, Oct. 8, 11am</h3>
<p>On Wednesday, October 8 at 11am, we will gather outside UNC’s South
Building, where AAUP officers along with UNC students will speak to
the press, make some announcements, and then walk to New West with
Professor Dwayne Dixon and his students. They’ll be returning to class
for the first time since September 29, when Professor Dixon was
<a href="https://www.dailytarheel.com/article/2025/10/breaking-university-dwayne-dixon-reinstated">wrongfully and harmfully placed on administrative
leave</a>. On
Friday, October 3, the administration <a href="https://ncnewsline.com/2025/10/03/unc-professor-dwayne-dixon-reinstated-after-suspension-over-anti-fascist-ties/">finally reinstated
Dixon</a>
after significant pressure from the community, including AAUP NC,
AAUP-Chapel Hill, UNC’s YDSA, UE-150, the ACLU of NC, and many of
Dixon’s admiring colleagues and students.</p>
<p>We’ll be cheering their return but also using this moment to lay out,
for faculty and the public, the many issues caused by UNC-Chapel
Hill’s administration’s egregious attacks on faculty and students’
academic freedom and First Amendment rights—not just last week’s
unnecessary and painful disruption of the fall semester for 300+
students, but also the <a href="https://www.aaup.org/news/aaup-president-calls-explanation-unc-chapel-hill-tenure-delay">harmful tenure vote delay for 33 faculty
members at UNC in
May</a>
and the <a href="https://www.dailytarheel.com/article/2025/08/university-hanes-palestinian-art-exhibit-covered-up">illegal removal and destruction of a student-created,
faculty-approved pro-Palestinian mural in
August</a>.</p>
<h3>Meet-up at Namu: Tuesday, Oct. 14, 4:30–6:30pm</h3>
<p>We’re gathering to celebrate our recently promoted and tenured
colleagues—and to raise a glass to our important collective wins:
fighting tenure delays, showing up for students’ freedom of speech,
and organizing to defend academic freedom—we have a lot to celebrate!
Join us at <a href="https://www.namudurham.com/">Namu</a> for conversations and
collegiality, and please invite your UNC colleagues.</p>
<h3>Academic Freedom Resources</h3>
<p>Please use <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScNLxqqVUcNQ8XIU7tRk2iAZcNX2GlNr_NZBcJGwTanrPnK0g/viewform">this
form</a>
to report any incidents of attacks on academic freedom or harassment
of academic workers since August 2025. This form is confidential and
will only be seen by officers and organizers for the NC AAUP.</p>
<h3>Conversation with Former Provost Chris Clemens, Wednesday, Oct. 8, 2pm</h3>
<p>The Administration of Free Speech: A TransparUNCy Conversation with
Former Provost Chris Clemens, Wednesday, Oct. 8, 2pm, Carroll Hall.</p>
<p>For this year’s First Amendment Day, TransparUNCy will be joined by
former Provost Chris Clemens for a discussion about some of the most
contentious conflicts in higher education and their implications for
free speech. How do debates around DEI, “institutional neutrality,”
student protest, tenure, and the ongoing politicization of university
governance affect the conditions for free speech on our campus?</p>
<p>Follow TransparUNCy here: <a href="https://uncaffirmativeactioncoalition.substack.com/">https://uncaffirmativeactioncoalition.substack.com/</a></p>
<h3>CITAP First Amendment Event at UNC, Wednesday, Oct. 8, 2:45–3:45pm</h3>
<p>CITAP First Amendment Event at UNC, Wednesday, Oct. 8, 2:45–3:45pm, Carroll Hall</p>
<p><a href="https://medialaw.unc.edu/events/citap1a_day_2025/">https://medialaw.unc.edu/events/citap1a_day_2025/</a></p>
<p>In collaboration with the What’s at Stake project
<a href="https://www.onthestakes.com/">https://www.onthestakes.com/</a>, join this timely discussion on the
role of First Amendment freedoms in protecting democracy.</p>
<p>The United States is backsliding into what political scientists call
“electoral autocracy,” where elections are held but there is not free
and fair competition. The President and his party are weaponizing the
state to weaken the political opposition and the journalism outlets,
media, platforms, and universities that can hold them accountable,
including through elections. At such a moment, the First Amendment
freedom to produce information and knowledge in the public interest
that safeguards democratic elections, processes, and norms is
crucial. This panel will provide a clear-eyed, research-based analysis
of what is at stake and argue for the right—and responsibility—of
media and platforms to serve as democratic gatekeepers and hold
elected leaders accountable for eroding checks on their power. At a
time when many university administrators and faculty would rather talk
about the hypothetical threats of AI than the wolves at the door,
panelists will detail the urgency of the existential threats to our
shared democratic life, the violent consequences of inaction such as
during the attempted coup on January 6th, and the ways that
journalism, platforms, and universities must rise to meet the moment
and fulfill their obligation of serving the public interest.</p>
<p>Panelists:</p>
<ul>
<li>Meredith D. Clark <a href="https://hussman.unc.edu/people/meredith-d-clark">https://hussman.unc.edu/people/meredith-d-clark</a>,
Associate Professor of Race and Political Communication at UNC
School of Journalism and Media; Co-Principal Investigator, UNC
Center for Information, Technology, and Public Life</li>
<li>Shannon C. McGregor
<a href="https://hussman.unc.edu/people/shannon-c-mcgregor">https://hussman.unc.edu/people/shannon-c-mcgregor</a>, Associate
Professor at UNC School of Journalism and Media; Co-Principal
Investigator, UNC Center for Information, Technology, and Public
Life</li>
<li>Daniel Kreiss <a href="https://hussman.unc.edu/people/daniel-kreiss">https://hussman.unc.edu/people/daniel-kreiss</a>, Edgar
Thomas Cato Distinguished Professor at UNC School of Journalism and
Media; Faculty Director, Co-Principal Investigator, UNC Center for
Information, Technology, and Public Life</li>
<li>Anika Collier Navaroli <a href="https://www.anikacolliernavaroli.com/">https://www.anikacolliernavaroli.com/</a>,
Assistant Professor of Professional Practice at Columbia Journalism
School; Reporting Fellow at Tech Policy Press</li>
</ul>
<h3>Rally in Support of Higher Education, Oct. 24, 2–4pm</h3>
<p>Right to Light: A Rally in Support of Higher Education, Chapel Hill,
Oct. 24 2–4pm, The Plaza, 140 W. Franklin, Chapel Hill, NC.</p>
<p>Keynote speaker: Professor Gene Nichol
<a href="https://law.unc.edu/people/gene-r-nichol/">https://law.unc.edu/people/gene-r-nichol/</a>, a distinguished professor
of law, commentator, and author of several books on North Carolina
politics, poverty, race, religion, and democracy. He was director of
the UNC Poverty Center (2008–2015) until it was closed by the Board of
Governors.</p>
<p>You can register to attend here
<a href="https://www.mobilize.us/mobilize/event/840735/">https://www.mobilize.us/mobilize/event/840735/</a>.</p>
<h3>Chapter Organizing</h3>
<p>We’re identifying chapter liaisons for departments and academic
units. If you’d like to volunteer, contact Erik Gellman at
<a href="mailto:esgellman@gmail.com">esgellman@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>If you would like to help with these weekly updates or help maintain
and update our chapter’s website and social media, please contact
Michael Palm at <a href="mailto:mwpalm@gmail.com">mwpalm@gmail.com</a>.</p>
<p>And everyone is welcome to join our <em>weekly working meetings Fridays
from Noon–1pm</em>, even if just to say hi and see what’s going on.</p>
<p><em>Note that we are using a new link for these meetings!</em></p>
<p><a href="https://unc.zoom.us/j/98472343156?pwd=WLsCiCkQcrOEsEmZwRri5p2S6PaaZR.1">https://unc.zoom.us/j/98472343156?pwd=WLsCiCkQcrOEsEmZwRri5p2S6PaaZR.1</a></p>
<p>Meeting ID: 984 7234 3156</p>
<p>Passcode: 305015</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UNC-CH AAUP Statement on Dwayne Dixon]]></title>
        <id>https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-10-01</id>
        <link href="https://unc-ch-aaup.org/news#2025-10-01"/>
        <updated>2025-10-01T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>AAUP NC and UNC-Chapel Hill AAUP condemn the egregious violation of
Professor Dwayne Dixon’s First Amendment rights to free speech and
free association, his Fourteenth Amendment right to due process, and
his <a href="https://www.aaup.org/issues-higher-education/academic-freedom">academic
freedom</a>.</p>
<p>See the <a href="/assets/unc-ch-aaup-statement-on-dwayne-dixon.pdf">full AAUP NC and UNC-Chapel Hill AAUP
statement</a> on UNC
administrators’ violations of Professor Dixon’s and his students’
rights.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>